whatscookingamerica.net 2019-11-30

# Privacy Policy, Whats Cooking America

### **What’s Cooking America – Privacy Policy**

What’s Cooking America is committed to maintaining the privacy and protection of your personal information. This privacy policy tells you about the information we collect on our website and how we use that information.

We care about protecting the privacy of children. We will not knowingly allow anyone under 16 to provide us any personally identifying information. Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any information about themselves (such as their names, email addresses, and phone numbers) over the Internet, to us or to anyone else. If you are under 16, please do not provide us with any personally identifying information (such as your name, your email address or your phone number).

#### **Use of Cookies on What’s Cooking America:**

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer or mobile device to help ensure that you get the best possible experience when you visit a website. The following cookies can be found on our web site.

#### **Web site Third Party Apps:**

[Yoast SEO](https://kb.yoast.com/kb/gdpr/)“ A tool that helps make whatscookingamerica.com site as search engine-friendly as possible.

**Newsletter Service: MailChimp**

**You have the right to be forgotten** : If you would like your email removed from the newsletter mailing list please contact bweller@whatscookingamerica.net

**Google Analytics**

Web Site Analytics Cookies

**Anonymous Information:  **We use anonymous information to analyze our Site traffic, but we do not examine this information for individually identifying information. In addition, we may use anonymous IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our site, or to display the content according to your preferences. Traffic and transaction information may also be shared with business partners and advertisers on an aggregate and anonymous basis.

#### **We use Google Analytics for the following purposes:**

**Tracking Information:  **Cookies to help us learn which areas of our site are useful and which areas need improvement.

**Click Tracking:  **Gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movements around the site and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Except as noted herein, we do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information.

**IP Addresses:** Each user’s IP address is logged with each visit and each action performed on our web site. This information is never provided to the third parties, except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, and is logged only for a temporary period of time. IP address information is linked to personal information and may be used in an effort to block a banned user from accessing the Site.

Google analytics data is stored indefinitely so that we can track the traffic of our web site.

#### **Visiting our Website from outside the US**

For visitors outside of the US, please be aware that your information may stored on servers in the US where our websites servers are located and operated. We take steps to assure protection of your privacy but please be aware that your laws may differ than those of the United States. By using our Website, you agree to having your information stored in our US based servers and third parties as stated in this Privacy Policy.

#### **California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below.

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have provided your personal information with the Site, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Site. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include sufficient detail about the public post(s) and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Site, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems, nor can we guarantee any cached or archived version of the site will remove such data.

#### **Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance:**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. We care about protecting children’s privacy. We won’t knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide personally identifying information. Children who are under 13 should not provide any information about themselves on the internet (including names, email addresses, and phone numbers).

#### **Third Party Advertising:**

We also use third party advertisements on What’s Cooking America to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes in order to: help manage ad campaigns, understand user interests and trends and deliver personalized content and advertising to you while you are on the Site or on other sites. PLEASE NOTE THAT WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE OR LIABLE FOR THE ACTS AND/OR OMISSIONS OF THIRD PARTY VENDORS.

#### **Affiliate Program Participation**

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

##### **Our  Affiliate Advertising Partners**

**Sortable:**

**Google AdSense:**

**LockerDome:**

#### **Amazon Associates Program Disclosure**

What’s Cooking America, Chehalem Publishing, LLC,  is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales. If affiliate links are used in a post, it will be disclosed and can be identified by the use of green text.

#### **Social Media:**

Cookies are also used with social media links that are used on our web site. When navigating to and from a social media web site, cookies are used. Example, if you hit Like on a Facebook icon.

**Social Media Partners**

Google+/Youtube

The important thing to remember about the use of cookies is; while some cookies are used to track your use of our website, they cannot be used to identify you personally or tell us who you are.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in security programs. Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [ads preference manager](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). (Alternatively, you can direct users to opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).)

**To Learn more about cookies and how to adjust your browser settings: Visit  **[ **www.aboutcookies.org**](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)  **or www.youronlinechoices.eu**

#### **How Your Information Will Be Used:**

**Personal Information:  **What’s Cooking America will not share your personal information with any third parties without your consent, except as necessary to provide you with the services offered by us or to comply with the law. We may also use your contact information to inform you of any changes to What’s Cooking America, or to send you additional information about What’s Cooking America. Information may also be shared with the above mentioned third party, advertising and social media partners as a normal function of our income producing business

**Disclosure of Personal Information:** We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on What’s Cooking America., (2) protect and defend the rights or property of What’s Cooking America or the users of this site, or (3) act under circumstances to protect the safety of the public or users of this site.

**Security:  **What’s Cooking America Recipes has security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information that we obtain from you, but we make no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, misuse, to you or to any third party arising out of any such loss, misuse, or alteration. What’s Cooking America is a hosted on a secure connection through a valid security certificate (HTTPS). Your data will be kept secure (or our third-party apps will) and that if a data breach occurs, you will be notified within 72 hours of that breach.  If you are under the age of 16, you must receive parental affirmative consent for you to be on your site.

**Third Party Websites:  **What’s Cooking America Recipes may contain links to other websites. If you choose to visit other websites, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those other websites, and it is your responsibility to review the privacy policies at those websites to confirm that you understand and agree with their policies.

**Updates and Changes:  **We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this privacy policy, simply by posting such change, update, or modification on What’s Cooking America and without any other notice to you. Any such change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the site. It is your responsibility to review this privacy policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with all of its terms.

#### **Trademark and Copyright Notices:**

You are welcome to like us on Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest Pin or Google+ share pages of this web site. You may also forward our emails to friends.

Unless otherwise noted, all content is developed by us and copyright 2019 What’s Cooking America doing business under our parent company as Chehalem Publishing, LLC.

**Using our photos:**

Please credit any photo you use with two links,  **one back to the direct recipe post**  and  **one back to whatscookingamerica.com.  **All photos taken by _What’s Cooking America  _are rights protected.  Failure to link back and credit our site as their source constitutes a copyright violation. Unless otherwise noted, all content and photography is © 2019 What’s Cooking America (doing business under our parent company of Chehalem Publishing, LLC)

For inquiries regarding the use, reproduction or purchase of photography seen here, please contact [Nancy](mailto:%20nhartman@whatscookingamerica.net).

#### **Disclosures and Disclaimers:**

All posts will be made by What’s Cooking America or guest columnist and all opinions contained in any page or post are mine or our columnists unless explicitly stated otherwise.  All information is intended for your general knowledge only and is not a substitute for medical advice or treatment for specific medical conditions. You should seek prompt medical care for any specific health issues. In addition, What’s Cooking America does not accept any responsibility for injury sustained as a result of following the advice or tips offered throughout this blog.  Please consult a medical professional for any specific nutrition, diet advice.

#### **How to Contact Us:**

Write to us at:

What’s Cooking America

6755 SW Mt. Bachelor Dr., Powell Butte, OR. 97753

**Email:  **nhartman@whatscookingamerica.net

This policy was last updated on October 29, 2019.
